<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | MIAlab</title>
    <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mindinaction.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mindinaction.github.io/media/icon_hub4dcace8ce2798ac95f15b515349aeea_1784_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inchara joins rolfslab and mialab</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-10-15-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-10-15-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am so happy to welcome Inchara to Berlin. She received a scholarship from the Berlin School of Mind and Brain to pursue her PhD on the interplay between actions, perception and memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September outlook</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-09-15-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-09-15-september/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you divide the lab year roughly into presenting science vs. creating science, then September is the month when we all come back to our labs and get busy tinkering, implementing and piloting new ideas. We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last few weeks doing just that and are still getting new input through our regular Reading Club, which everyone actively attends. Our team is now almost complete for the next few months (but wait for the next post) and I am happy to work with such a wonderful team that is highly motivated to do good science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the lab Laura</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-08-01-laura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-08-01-laura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are very happy to welcome Laura van Zantwijk as a new PhD student in the MIAlab. Laura did her Master in Utrecht and has already contributed to many successful research projects on active perception. Welcome to Berlin Laura. We are so happy to have you here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on causality and spatial relations in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-07-22-ripe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-07-22-ripe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We participated at the spontaneous RIPE workshop in Berlin. What a great opportunity to learn more about relations from so many smart people. Hopefully, this workshop will take place again next year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint on sensorimotor awareness</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-07-03-preprintjan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-07-03-preprintjan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am so incredibly happy that this preprint on sensorimotor awareness with Jan Klanke as first author is available on biorxiv. Jan has created a wonderful new paradigm to measure microsaccade sensitivity. There are so many exciting methodological finesses in the study that together highlight the role of intention in sensorimotor awareness. See more here &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.02.601661&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.02.601661&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MIAlab at VSS</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-05-15-vss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-05-15-vss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the annual highlights in our research calendar is just around the corner. The MIAlab is flying to VSS. Sven will be giving a talk on Saturday with the title &amp;ldquo;What Newton did not know about Newton&amp;rsquo;s cradle: Separating visual routines for cause and effect&amp;rdquo; in the talk session &amp;ldquo;Perception of Relations, Intuitive Physics.&amp;rdquo; A lot of other cool talks are in the same session and we are very excited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Siri in the MIAlab</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-05-01-siri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-05-01-siri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted that Siri is now starting as a student assistant in the lab. She will be a great help to us in collecting data and we are already looking forward to programming new stimuli together with her. Siri is now officially the first lab member in our still young lab. Welcome Siri!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab visit in Oxford</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-02-01-oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-02-01-oxford/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were in Oxford for a few days after being invited by Dejan Draschkow and his lab for a workshop on combining eye tracking and EEG in virtual reality. Felix Klotzsche gave a wonderful introduction, motivating but also highlighting some important considerations when using VR as a tool for cognitive neuroscience. On the last day, we had the pleasure of presenting our memory studies using eye movements, EEG and VR at the BEACON seminar. Thanks to our host we had the best time in Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply as a student research assistant</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-02-01-call-for-shk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-02-01-call-for-shk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are currently enrolled as a student and would like to work in our laboratory in Berlin, then this job may be of interest to you. You will support us in collecting data for psychophysical experiments and gain insights into our day-to-day research work. If this sounds interesting, please apply by 14 February.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for PhD position</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-01-17-call-for-phd-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-01-17-call-for-phd-position/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The call for our first Phd position in the lab is now online. If you would like to work on the perception of causality over the next few years, please apply by 14 FEB 2024. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindinaction.github.io/author/open-phd-position/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://mindinaction.github.io/author/open-phd-position/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://haushalt-und-personal.hu-berlin.de/de/personal/stellenausschreibungen/wiss-mitarbeiter-in-m-w-d-mit-vorauss-3-4-teilzeitbeschaeftigung-e-13-tv-l-hu-drittmittelfinanzierung-befristet-fuer-3-jahre&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://haushalt-und-personal.hu-berlin.de/de/personal/stellenausschreibungen/wiss-mitarbeiter-in-m-w-d-mit-vorauss-3-4-teilzeitbeschaeftigung-e-13-tv-l-hu-drittmittelfinanzierung-befristet-fuer-3-jahre&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When applying, please refer to the number DR/023/24 in your application. I am looking forward to meeting you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch of the lab website</title>
      <link>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-01-01-the-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindinaction.github.io/post/24-01-01-the-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a website. If you are interested in studying the interplay between actions and memory, or the perception of causality, please consider joining the lab in Berlin. Watch this space for new positions over the next couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be more than happy to discuss possibilities for you to join us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
